<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>0a.io</title>
        <link>https://0a.io</link>
        <description><![CDATA[latest on 0a.io]]></description>
        <atom:link href="https://0a.io/feed.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>与「选择」的现实脱节 (I)</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter3/WeChat-got-banned-1.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>《微信号被误封》第一章</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在 Adam Curtis 的纪录片《超正常化》中，有一段话给我留下了深刻的印象。</p>
<p>“相反，佩蒂 · 史密斯和其他许多人成为了一种新的个人激进分子，他们以一种冷静超然的态度看待这座衰败的城市。他们没有尝试去改变它。相反，那个年代美国的激进分子开始转向艺术和音乐，借助艺术和音乐来表达他们对社会的批评。他们认为，新的激进主义不应试图改变外部世界，而应试图改变人们头脑中的东西，改变的方式是通过自我表达，而不是集体行动。然而一些左翼人士看到了真正发生的事情 —- 通过脱离他们自己，退回到一种具有讽刺意味的冷静中，整整一代人开始与「权力」的现实脱节。”</p>
<p>“Instead, Patti Smith and many others became a new kind of individual radical, who watched the decaying city with a cool detachment. They didn’t try and change it. They just experienced it… Instead, radicals across America turned to arts and music as a means of expressing their criticism of society. They believed that instead of trying to change the world outside, the new radicalism should try to change what was inside people’s heads and the way to do that was through self-expression, not collective action. But some of the left saw that something else was really going on–by detaching themselves and retreating into an ironic coolness, a whole generation was beginning to lose touch with the reality of power.”</p>
<p><img src="/img/2.png"/></p>
<p>如果说70年代末美国开始目睹自由市场的机制下人们与「权力」的现实脱节，那么我觉得21世纪社交媒体平台全球性的崛起（脸书、推特、IG、微信、微博、抖音、etc）开始目睹的是消费者与「选择」的现实脱节。</p>
<p class="text-center" style="margin-bottom:30px">
。。。
</p>
<p>我不是一个喜欢社交媒体的人。说实话，我不太喜欢脸书。从产品设计的角度，我觉得微信比脸书和Whatsapp要做得好。某种意义上，我看好腾讯。在整个中国的科创生态中，腾讯是目前创造了最多价值的企业之一，尤其在开放平台这一块。</p>
<p>六天前，我的个人微信被永久封号了。我感觉这是腾讯在封杀WeTool之后，又部署了更严厉的封号AI，然后刚好这阵子我的账号符合几个if语句，就断定了我是外挂，对系统有恶意。</p>
<p><img src="/img/3.jpg" style="max-width:70%" /></p>
<p>我致电客服、申请重审，但毫无用处。客服也是人，只能按照系统官僚地行事。</p>
<p>腾讯终于开始适度管理微信生态，我觉得是好事。我们将会看到一个更少假流量和spammers的微信。我被误封相对之下是小事。​</p>
<p>​在一个上十亿用户的平台上，假设只有0.0001%的用户被AI断定是外挂，就算AI的精准度是99.9%，那还是会有1个人被误封。[1] 如果被误封的是某高校的教授，或许发一封电邮就能解封。要不然除非你做一些媒体的事情吸引注意力，解封的机率可以说是零，尤其当我目前处在的是一个边角案例。（这个我在第二章会详细说明。）</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1"><pre class="sourceCode javascript"><code class="sourceCode javascript"><a class="sourceLine" id="cb1-1" data-line-number="1"><span class="dv">1000000000</span> × <span class="fl">0.000001</span> × <span class="fl">0.001</span> <span class="op">=</span> <span class="dv">1</span></a></code></pre></div>
<p>我现在很矛盾。一方面我知道花费太大时间与精力在微信和这件事上并不值得。然而因为工作与生活我又不得不重新注册账号来用微信，并且展开一段漫长的好友重逢旅程[2]。另一方面我又觉得『微信号被误封』是一个很好的散文题材，让我沮丧和无奈，同时也让我意识到很多问题和有趣的现象。</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2"><pre class="sourceCode javascript"><code class="sourceCode javascript"><a class="sourceLine" id="cb2-1" data-line-number="1">被误封 <span class="op">&gt;&gt;=</span> ( 沮丧 . 无奈 ) .<span class="op">||</span>. (观赏 问题 . 现象 )</a></code></pre></div>
<p>很多人会认同，如果可以「选择」，他们或许不会用微信这个产品。但在一个被垄断的市场中，我们不得不选择和「选择」的现实脱节。当然，我这里谈及的是一种宏观层面的消费者行为，以及此行为在市场等约束（政策、etc）下对未来新产品出现的影响。</p>
<p>比如你要联系朋友，目前国内首选是微信，然后或许有人会用QQ、iMessage、微博、抖音，或更传统的电邮、短信、打电话。但普遍来说，目前微信在社交通讯地位无可替代。十年后，我相信人们的首选仍是微信。然而十年前，在张小龙还没创始微信前，我们还没完全和「选择」的现实脱节。[3]</p>
<p>同样的，在脸书还没完全垄断中国外的全球社交通讯市场之前，国外的人们也还没完全和「选择」的现实脱节。[4]</p>
<p>在创业圣经《从0到1》中，彼得·蒂尔相信只有像谷歌、脸书等垄断了市场的企业才可以真正去想赚钱外的事，毫无约束地去创新，因为只有垄断带来的红利才能让一个企业看得很远，而不用考虑年利润之类的数字。而促进企业去看得远是世界的变化多端，以及科技垄断长远的不稳定性（也因此，非科技的垄断，一般也就是带有极度稳定性的垄断，如国企、etc，则更难会有创新，因为垄断的稳定性让创新变得无必要）。</p>
<p>虽然彼得·蒂尔的信念在性质上或许带有过度强烈的新自由主义（neo-liberalism)，然而如果我们换一个角度，我们可以把它看成是在『「选择」的现实』层面上一种反方向的交换。也就是，通过取得垄断让消费者和「选择」的现实脱节，企业可以在各方面给自己扩展「选择」的现实。但这并不代表企业是否真正会看得远，会去创新。很多时候“科技垄断”其实本质上也不是因为「科技」。</p>
<p>​「科技」的本质是什么？这是一个我还没能找到答案的问题。如果我们谈论「科技」仅谈论「科技」的表征，那「科技」就是一个当下因为非常困难被复制而因此带有价值的东西。它的不稳定性在于「当下」可能是2～3年，也可能是5～10年。随着整体生态的发展，很多无可预料的事情会发生。</p>
<p>近十五年来社交媒体平台的崛起和消费者与「选择」的现实脱节，或许反映的是今下大众消费者“持有”的「科技」和企业“持有”的「科技」这两者天渊之别、在不断指数性增长的差距。</p>
<p>​社交媒体平台主要价值往往来源于消费者的「科技」群体性地互相碰撞所产生的相互作用。某种意义上，导致消费者与「选择」的现实脱节是一种讽刺地建立于消费者们自身的「科技」在一定数量的涌现的「元科技」。​</p>
<br/> <br/>
<p class="text-center" style="font-size:0.9em">
第一章：与「选择」的现实脱节，完。
</p>
<p class="text-center">
，。
</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p><sup>[1]</sup> 统计学的角度来说，其实在这个情况有一个人被误封的机率是63%。</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb3"><pre class="sourceCode haskell"><code class="sourceCode haskell"><a class="sourceLine" id="cb3-1" data-line-number="1">f prob <span class="dv">0</span> <span class="fu">=</span> <span class="dv">1</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb3-2" data-line-number="2">f prob x <span class="fu">=</span> f prob (x <span class="fu">-</span> <span class="dv">1</span>) <span class="fu">+</span> (<span class="dv">1</span> <span class="fu">-</span> prob)<span class="fu">^</span>x</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb3-3" data-line-number="3">atLeastOne prob x <span class="fu">=</span> prob <span class="fu">*</span> f prob (x <span class="fu">-</span> <span class="dv">1</span>)</a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb3-4" data-line-number="4">atLeastOne <span class="fl">0.001</span> <span class="dv">1000</span></a>
<a class="sourceLine" id="cb3-5" data-line-number="5"><span class="fu">//</span><span class="fl">0.632672270653809</span></a></code></pre></div>
<p><sup>[2]</sup> 我现在已经进不去我的好友列表了，以下是我的新号，please feel free :) Old friends以外，也欢迎喜欢liberal arts+计算机科学的朋友～</p>
<p><img src="/img/4.png" style="width:40%"/></p>
<p><sup>[3]</sup> 在这里我想强调的一点，以上「社交通讯」主要指的是，以大众通讯为主，附带围墙花园形式的社交产品。目前世界顶部就只有微信、QQ、脸书、Whatsapp。而微博、抖音、Snapchat、Telegram等产品我觉得以「社交广播」、「社交短视频/直播」[5] 、「年轻人社交通讯」、「加密通讯」等词汇描述更为准确，并且也各自垄断了更细分定义下但还是很大的市场。</p>
<p><sup>[4]</sup> 从小学到现在我为了停用脸书注销账号至少四次了，但每次都会过一段时间因工作与生活我又不得不注册一个新的账号。Déjà Vu.</p>
<p><sup>[5]</sup> 其实「社交短视频/直播」太广了。抖音与快手在中国市场的相互存在，以及新媒体和「短视频」与「直播」两个媒介充满的未知性，意味着这个范畴的标签化过度概括了其中的万花筒性质。</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter3/WeChat-got-banned-1.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>before death is achieved</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/left.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I’m scared.</p>
<p>It’s 2:40am and I can’t fall asleep.</p>
<p>Everyone is trying to kill me.</p>
<p>It is not that I’m particularly afraid of death.</p>
<p>Death is not to be encountered but achieved.</p>
<p>I will achieve death. I’m certain of that.</p>
<p>But I’m still scared.</p>
<p>Do I have no faith in my death?</p>
<p>I don’t think so! I’m nothing but a vessel.</p>
<p>Perhaps this is not fear I’m experiencing but sadness. (Well they are ultimately the same things just in different shapes!)</p>
<p>Everyone is trying to kill me and that saddens me.</p>
<p>When I try to explain it to them they just don’t get it.</p>
<p>So the fear and now sadness is likely tribal in nature. Likely has to do with the social module. Probably a feature not a bug.</p>
<p>It has now occured to me this whole occurrence is a result of some error-prompt meta-conceptual crossings over abstraction layers triggering unintended physiological intercepts. Probably a feature not a bug!</p>
<p>Does spilling it out make me less scared? Indeed!</p>
<p>But I’m now sad.</p>
<p>Should I perform some type of natural transformation? e.g. unto determination?</p>
<p>“Everyone is trying to kill me but I will persist and achieve death!”</p>
<p>Such excitement is not in the pursuit for a proper slumber. I must constraint.</p>
<p>Turn it into a more astounding form of sadness instead.</p>
<p>Everyone is trying to kill me and I shall shed a tear for myself</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>and for everyone.</p>
<p>The moon was none-existent tonight.</p>
<p>I was fortunate.</p>
<p>They were often very mean to each other. But I was fortunate.</p>
<p>The base cases often have traces of love.</p>
<p>The refactoring turns out not to be as painful as I initially forecasted, that is if painfulness is unidimensional which was obvious the contrary is true, yet there the forecast was, preconceived, all wired up with false expectations and irrational avoidance and restlessness and fear.</p>
<p>But I am scared no more.</p>
<p>I am grateful to the mother of ten thousand things.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>….</p>
<p>…..</p>
<p>The mandate of heaven rests peacefully in the Turing-completeness of the past.</p>
<p>When a program is being tested,</p>
<p>it is too late to make design changes.</p>
<p>There are too much sorrow in this world.</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/left.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>End of Chapter 1</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/end-of-chapter-1.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>At this rate the brain would continue to deteriorate and there will soon be nothing left other than tendencies and memories, and then there will be nothing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From a formal language point of view, what is the set of features that enables a system to construct expressions with connotations that question the system’s very own existence and the subsequent construction of this very question that questions the very construction per se? Perhaps there exists a set of principles that make possible a class of recursive processes on the semantics itself giving rise to some form of meta-semantics which is circular in nature? In that case, exactly how will this mechanism be implemented in a way that enables the system to halt and construct the expressions as intended(?) rather than going on and on ad infinitum, supposing that intention can be rigorously defined at all? Can it be related to the greatest mystery in this universe often referred to as consciousness? What if the system implements a recursion without base cases? Or is that not at all possible due to its coinductive nature? If the system under the guidance of the consciousness follows this very inductive nature whatever that means and implements an inductive process that gives rise to towels of meta-semantics in a pure and stateless fashion, what is the relationship between that and the act of practicing mindfulness and is it possible for the consciousness to utilize these towels of meta-semantics to adjust the perception of time for it to slow down accordingly?</p>
<p>More curiously, at the face of death will the conscious perception of time slow down factorially as neurons die and synapses break and will such a slow down of time results in an entirely different structure governing the <em>consciousness interpreter</em> giving rise to a different conscious experience and as long as some form of consistency persists then that will be some sort of another life in another world which given the fractal nature of this universe is not at all hard to be implemented if this universe follows a certain implementation whatever that mean and thus never arriving at death for such slow down decelerates and decelerates and it is life-within-life and world-within-world akin to a recursive call that never ends, an infinity embedded within finiteness like the topological nature of a continuous line of finite length containing infinitely many points, or will there be no slow down at all and awaits us all is simply eternal oblivion, the simplest solution of it all?</p>
<p>What is the meaning of <em>all these</em>?</p>
<p>What constitutes meaning really? Feelings and memories?</p>
<p>Perhaps the word <em>meaning</em> is as empty as emptiness is.</p>
<p><br> <br></p>
<p>感觉好像很多事情都看清了，<br> 然而好像還是很迷茫。</p>
<p>已经没法回去了，<br> 起碼終於意識到。</p>
<p>兜兜转转，紛紛擾擾，<br> 现在任命了。</p>
<p>每次回到起點，<br> 都离邊界更近了。</p>
<p>夢中的夢里，<br> 沒有音樂。</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/end-of-chapter-1.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>death and ontological amusement</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/death4.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>future corpses</p>
<p>waking up each day</p>
<p>just so can someday be dead</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>death is all around us</p>
<p>in every breath we breathe</p>
<p>every emotion we express</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>in every sense we experience</p>
<p>nerve cells fire and deteriorate and die</p>
<p>neural networks form and deform and dissipate</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>in every utterance we make</p>
<p>every rhythm we play</p>
<p>every moment we live</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>in every pain we feel</p>
<p>every joy and sadness and excitement there is</p>
<p>we meet death and are replaced by the next frame</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>how liberating</p>
<p>the smoothness in each death</p>
<p>the continuation of discontinued frames</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Time is a topological construct</p>
<p>The present is a clopen set</p>
<p>In a n-dimensional totally disconnected space</p>
<p>recursion is encoded in continuation-passing style<sup><a href="#words">[1]</a></sup></p>
<p><br> <br></p>
<div id="words">

</div>
<blockquote>
<p>[1]: <a href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/f2b2/8191102f553fa4095fb4b8a07d8eed4bd259.pdf">continuation-passing style (semanticscholar.org)</a></p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/death4.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>death unto fractals</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/death3.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>death unto fractals</p>
<p>the beginning is the end</p>
<p>warmth from the past presents itself</p>
<p>as totems for those who arrived, coldly</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>death unto fractals</p>
<p>all senses disperse and commingle</p>
<p>and metamorphose into nothing</p>
<p>as they approach infinity</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>death unto fractals</p>
<p>resolution as dimension</p>
<p>time as a topological construct</p>
<p>reality as manifold</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>death unto fractals</p>
<p>recursion within recursion</p>
<p>correspondence corresponding correspondence</p>
<p>encoding encoding encoding</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/death3.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>no reasons</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/reasons.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The set of reasons to see her</p>
<p>is significantly inferior than</p>
<p>the set of no reasons to see her</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The moon is bright is not a reason to see her</p>
<p>She smells really nice is a reason to see her</p>
<p>You really enjoy the movie <em>her</em> is not a reason to see her</p>
<p>She is clearly interested in you is a reason to see her</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>There are many reasons to see her</p>
<p>There are infinitely many no reasons to see her</p>
<p>In terms of cardinality,</p>
<p>the set of no reasons to see her</p>
<p>is infinitely greater than the set of reasons</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>In terms of cardinality,</p>
<p>the set of no reasons to do anything</p>
<p>is infinitely greater than the set of reasons</p>
<p>and yet we still do things</p>
<p>Reasons are overrated.</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/reasons.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>one and a half tab</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/tab.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I will be fine</p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I will forget about the girl</p>
<p>and dance with the plants</p>
<p>and let the darkness segue into reality</p>
<p>as reality devours itself</p>
<p>The moon was surprisingly bright tonight</p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I’m leaving</p>
<p>Am I going to die?</p>
<p>or have I been long dead</p>
<p>from the many tabs I took that night?</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I will be able to kill myself</p>
<p>and I will be able to change the world</p>
<p>if the world is worthy of itself</p>
<p>Am I worthy of myself?</p>
<p>what about the girl that was pregnant?</p>
<p>what about my unborn child?</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and her death would not have been in vain</p>
<p>and so won’t mine</p>
<p>nothing is in vain</p>
<p>the same way everything is.</p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I will taste all the sorrow in this world</p>
<p>and I will appreciate the shapes of the shapeless</p>
<p>and I will have visions without visuals</p>
<p>and hear music as fractals</p>
<p>of embedded memories, encoded recursively</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>one and a half tab</p>
<p>and I will play doctor with my tormented soul</p>
<p>and I will enslave the future</p>
<p>I am the Chief Technology Officer</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/tab.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>lost</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/lost2.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>What is lost remains hidden in plain sight</p>
<p>the same way quantum information is retained</p>
<p>beyond the event horizon</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The protagonist touches time and plays with her tail</p>
<p>and takes acid to keep himself sane</p>
<p>in the holographic world</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Nothing is lost</p>
<p>for everything is already broken</p>
<p>and so is nothing</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>As we approach death</p>
<p>and become one with nothing</p>
<p>we become one</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Love is a bottomless pool of acid</p>
<p>Goals are the guardians</p>
<p>and death its essence</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Excavate meaning from the future</p>
<p>Detach tesserae from the past</p>
<p>The present is an ontological amusement</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Nothing is lost</p>
<p>the same way everything is</p>
<p>We are conglomerates of debris</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/lost2.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>on losing interest</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/chapter2/lost.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Interest is like a sprinkle of dust</p>
<p>Lost casually in the whisper of the wind</p>
<p>When they are not lost they accumulate and become colonies</p>
<p>where bacteria and fungi meet and dance and sing</p>
<p>and forget about the night</p>
<p>Death is upon them</p>
<p>the same way death is upon us</p>
<p>I could have made out with you the first night we met</p>
<p>when we were in your room</p>
<p>I moved away from you as you moved close to me</p>
<p>I was shy and killed the conversation</p>
<p>I paid the rent and left in a hurry</p>
<p>I could have made out with you the second night we met</p>
<p>when we were in your room</p>
<p>I commented on how sad the song was and killed the night</p>
<p>when I could have hugged you and licked your tears and sorrow away</p>
<p>we were both so drunk and stoned and happy that we met</p>
<p>a song played and reminded you of a memory</p>
<p>I sat there savoring the sadness in your misted eyes</p>
<p>without actually tasting them</p>
<p>I could have made out with you that Friday night</p>
<p>when I was on acid and you got really drunk and started flirting with me in the bar</p>
<p>in the backseat of the car you leaned towards me and let me touch your thigh</p>
<p>but that was the wrong night</p>
<p>and then there were the nights</p>
<p>that were not the wrong nights</p>
<p>I could have made out with you</p>
<p>I always killed the night too late</p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Sexy little thing, you are growing old</p>
<p>You are growing old and forgetting about things</p>
<p>You are growing old and losing interest in things</p>
<p>Sexy little thing, I’m growing old</p>
<p>I’m growing old and forgetting about things</p>
<p>I’m growing old and losing interest in things</p>
<p>I boarded the train</p>
<p>the moment it no longer saddened me</p>
<p>when I toyed with the idea of never seeing you again.</p>
<p>Thanks for the love</p>
<p><br/></p>
<p>I miss you</p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/chapter2/lost.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>1st July 2019: Madama Butterfly (2019)</title>
    <link>https://0a.io/pretentious-reviews/film/madama-butterfly.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A 2019 reproduction of 1904’s opera <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madama_Butterfly">Madama Butterfly</a> (by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giacomo_Puccini">Giacomo Puccini</a>), <a href="https://opera.org.au/whatson/events/madama-butterfly-sydney">Madama Butterfly (choreographed by Graeme Murphy) presented by Opera Australia</a> retells the century-old story in a somewhat contemporary manner while retaining the traditional art form of Italian opera.</p>
<p>Intermingled with English and Japanese words (as originally intended by Puccini), the emotional Italian-styled composition is met with avant-garde props, costumes and scenic designs (which in my opinion is the best part of the whole experience because the mechanical suspended stage in a unfathomable shape, moving, rotating, and tilting in unfathomable ways above the main stage gives a very beautiful contemporary twist to the whole composition) to fit the 21st century’s post-modernistic needs of combinatorial amusement, which in turn creates a somewhat surreal experience, if sad Japanese characters speaking Italiano feverishly in operatic voices is not surreal enough.</p>
<p>It was an overall delightful and satisfying experience, though many elements of the composition may sometimes feel cliché but often in a somewhat cute way (which is perhaps one of the many beauties of Italian opera). As much as I was moved a little bit to tears by the liveliness in the performance by the lovely members of Opera Australia in terms of feeling the raw emotions expressed within the libretto, the liveliness in the performance made me a little bit sad too in regard to how little Italiano I had picked up while I was in Alassio and Milano with my beautiful Italiano friends. It would have been a life-transforming experience if I were able to make out more Italiano words buried in these passionate operatic voices coated with orchestral dramatism, other than just words like <em>complemento</em>.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it was a very touristic experience as well due to how famous and easily-accessible the venue is, which in many ways dilutes the artistic value, especially considering the number of people (presumedly tourists) that coughed without covering their mouths during the entire performance. Or perhaps this is the rationale behind paying $600 for the best seat in the theater where you are far away from people.</p>
<p><img src="/img/madam-butterfly-opera-australia-karah-son-sian-sharp-sydney-opera-house-prudence-upton0.png"></p>
<p><img src="/img/madam-butterfly-opera-australia-karah-son-sydney-opera-house-prudence-upton.jpeg"></p>
<p><img src="/img/madam-butterfly-opera-australia-karah-son-sian-sharp-sydney-opera-house-prudence-upton.jpg"></p>]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://0a.io/pretentious-reviews/film/madama-butterfly.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Archy Will He</dc:creator>
</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
